const e="commerce",i=200,t=108,o=[{id:441,question:"The type of labour that makes use of physical effort in production processes is the ",option:{a:"unskilled labour",b:"skilled labour",c:"blue-collar job",d:"white-collar job"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:442,question:"The assembling of products into usable forms is known as ",option:{a:"creation ",b:"manufacturing ",c:"construction ",d:"formation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:443,question:"The final link in the chain of distribution is ",option:{a:"Middlemen ",b:"wholesaling ",c:"consumer ",d:"retailing "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:444,question:"A country is said to be experiencing an unfavourable balance of trade if her",option:{a:"exports exceed imports ",b:"visible exports  exceed  visible imports ",c:"imports and export are equal ",d:"visible imports exceed visible exports "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:445,question:"Trading position of Nigeria is the same as her ",option:{a:"desire  to trade with many countries",b:"willingness to grant credit to foreigners ",c:"balance of trade ",d:"terms of trade"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:446,question:"The role of customs and excise authority includes the ",option:{a:"provision of a good transport system to facilitate imports and exports ",b:"provision of security at the port ",c:"control of the flow of goods in and out of the country ",d:"provision of dockyards for ship repairs "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:447,question:"The document lodged with the customs authorities before a ship can leave the port is a ",option:{a:"shipping note ",b:"ship report ",c:"ship manifest",d:"dock warrant "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:448,question:"The document which must be endorsed by the ambassador of a country of destination before shipment of goods is a ",option:{a:"consular invoice ",b:"certificate of origin ",c:"bill of lading ",d:"closed indent "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:449,question:"A country’s terms of trade are said to improve when the ratio of her export ",option:{a:"decreases ",b:"remains constant ",c:"increases ",d:"equals import"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:450,question:"Which of the following advertising medium appeals to only the literate it the society?",option:{a:"Radio advertising ",b:"Print Media advertising ",c:"Television advertising ",d:"Cinema advertising "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:451,question:"The two main forms of communication are ",option:{a:"oral and written ",b:"verbal and non-verbal ",c:"e-mail and fax",d:"traditional and modern media "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:452,question:"The most reliable and efficient means of conveying urgent documents is through",option:{a:"postal order ",b:"ordinary letters ",c:"registered letters ",d:"courier services"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:453,question:"An undertaking given by a person to another assuring his integrity is ",option:{a:"proximate clause ",b:"fidelity guarantee ",c:"subrogation ",d:"insurable interest "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:454,question:"If Mr. N takes a fire insurance policy with average clause, his compensation will be ",option:{a:"N5, 000",b:"N7, 500",c:"N70, 000",d:"N75,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:455,question:"The difference between indemnity insurance and non-indemnity insurance is that the latter provides ",option:{a:"cover for exporters against risks ",b:"cover for importers against risks ",c:"full payment to the insured ",d:"consolation payment to the insured "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:456,question:"An importance of warehousing is in the ",option:{a:"production of goods ",b:"transportation of goods ",c:"Importation of goods ",d:"repackaging of goods"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:457,question:"In order to increase the capital owned, a sole trader may ",option:{a:"seek for bank loan ",b:"issue debentures ",c:"acquire extra shop fittings on credit ",d:"draw less of his profit for personal use"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:458,question:"A business partner who provides capital but abstains from participation in administration of a firm is a ",option:{a:"general partner ",b:"nominal partner ",c:"secret partner ",d:"dormant partner "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:459,question:"Which of the following will NOT be stated in a Memorandum of Association? ",option:{a:"Name clause ",b:"Rights of shareholders ",c:"object clause ",d:"Registered office"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:460,question:"The amount of authorized capital that shareholders have subscribed to is ",option:{a:"issued share capital ",b:"authorized share capital ",c:"owner’s equity ",d:"working capital "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:461,question:`The rate of turnover of a firm in a given year is 5 times while the average stock is 
 N12.500. what is the turnover of the firm? 
`,option:{a:"N24,000",b:"N46,500",c:"N62, 500",d:"N65,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:462,question:"A lawyer that defrauds his client may be derobed by the Nigerian Bar Association in order to ",option:{a:"protect other lawyers ",b:"protect the integrity of the association",c:"compensate the affected client ",d:"prevent the client from sueing the association "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:463,question:"In the Nigeria GSM industry, a parliament is organized by the Nigerian Communication Commission in order to ",option:{a:"increase profit of service providers ",b:"protect the interest of government ",c:"encourage more people into the business ",d:"protect the interest of consumers "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:464,question:"Trade Fairs in Nigeria are organized by ",option:{a:"the Federal Government ",b:"Manufactures’ Association of Nigeria",c:"Ministry of Commerce and industry ",d:"Chambers of commerce"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:465,question:"Money is generally acceptable for transactions due to",option:{a:"the legal backing ",b:"the rule of law ",c:"it’s acceptability in the global market ",d:"the Central Bank Governor’s signature "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:466,question:"Which of the following is a quality of money?  ",option:{a:"Availability",b:"Scarcity  ",c:"Indivisibility ",d:"Convertibility "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:467,question:"Money can simply be referred to as a ",option:{a:"measure of value",b:"standard of value",c:"means of settlement ",d:"durable asset for doing business"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:468,question:"Gilt-edged securities are issued mainly by ",option:{a:"individuals ",b:"non-governmental organizations",c:"government ",d:"multi-national companies "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:469,question:"The initial function of a manager is ",option:{a:"setting up an organization ",b:"coordinating ",c:"planning ",d:"provision of welfare package "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:470,question:"The most suitable organizational structure for small or medium-sized enterprises is ",option:{a:"line structure ",b:"staff structure ",c:"committee structure ",d:"functional structure "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:471,question:"In a staff-authority relationship, the opinion of a specialist is one department to another is ",option:{a:"a directive ",b:"an advice ",c:"a command",d:"a delegation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:472,question:"Management of a business involves he development of ideas for the ",option:{a:"distribution of goods and services that human wants",b:"transportation of goods and services that goods and services that human wants ",c:"transfer of little of ownership of goods and services to individuals.",d:"production of goods and services that satisfy human needs."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:473,question:"Which of the following is used as a pricing policy? ",option:{a:"packaging ",b:"market selection ",c:"labeling ",d:"market skimming "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:474,question:"The essential utility derived from the use of a product is known as ",option:{a:"augmented benefit",b:"branded benefit ",c:"core benefit ",d:"formal benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:475,question:"The breaking down of a market into separate and identifiable elements is known as ",option:{a:"differentiation ",b:"segmentation ",c:"skimming ",d:"penetration "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:476,question:"A contract that is acknowledged before the law court is referred to as ",option:{a:"informal contract",b:"formal contract ",c:"contract of records ",d:"specialty contract "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:477,question:"An agent employed to sell goods delivered to him by the principal is referred to as a ",option:{a:"Special agent ",b:"del credere agent ",c:"factor ",d:"universal agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:478,question:"A motor dealer who agreed to sell a car to Mr. X but sold and delivered it to Mr. Y on the delivery date agreed with Mr. X. He has discharged the contract by ",option:{a:"performance ",b:"frustration ",c:"an agreement ",d:"breach "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:479,question:"A contract can be terminated through ",option:{a:"physical combat ",b:"family intervention ",c:"frustration ",d:"consultation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:480,question:"The right of retain possession of goods until the contract price is paid is referred to as ",option:{a:"a promise ",b:"ultra vires ",c:"a branch ",d:"a lien "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:481,question:"The sole legal right held by the author to publish his book is a ",option:{a:"trademark ",b:"copyright ",c:"patent right ",d:"book mark"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:482,question:"The process of transferring data from one computer to another is referred to as ",option:{a:"down loading ",b:"faxing ",c:"browsing ",d:"decoding "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:483,question:"The physical component of a computer system is ",option:{a:"software ",b:"hardware ",c:"hard disk",d:"floppy disk "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:484,question:"A computer accessory through which information can be retrieved is the ",option:{a:"hard disk ",b:"input  device ",c:"control unit ",d:"floppy disk "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:485,question:"The type of computer application software used mainly for management information is ",option:{a:"Corel draw ",b:"AutoCAD",c:"data base",d:"word perfect"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:486,question:"To meet security requirement before gaining access to data, a computer operator supplies ",option:{a:"an e-mail address ",b:"a yahoo address ",c:"a password ",d:"a modem"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:487,question:"A major factor that affects business operations is ",option:{a:"technology ",b:"supply ",c:"product ",d:"rivalry "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:488,question:"The environmental hazard that is most difficult to control is ",option:{a:"land pollution",b:"water pollution ",c:"air pollution",d:"political unrest "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:539,question:"Commercialization is good for the Nigerian economy because it",option:{a:"creates room for competition",b:"increases the cost of living",c:"leads to the reduction of workforce",d:"leads to uneven distribution of wealth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:540,question:"Obtaining feedback on the quality and performance of competing products of different manufacturers, explains the retailer’s function of",option:{a:"after sales service",b:"granting to credits to consumers",c:"market research",d:"stocking variety of goods"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:541,question:"The direct contact of a seller with potential buyers with a view to making sales is called",option:{a:"advertising",b:"personal selling",c:"public relations",d:"publicity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:542,question:"The process of dividing a total market into groups made up of people with similar need refers to marketing",option:{a:"function",b:"mix",c:"research",d:"segmentation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:543,question:"The final link in the chain of distribution is the",option:{a:"agent",b:"consumer",c:"manufacturer",d:"retailer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:544,question:"Platinum Habib Bank Plc. is an example of __ bank.",option:{a:"central",b:"commercial",c:"development",d:"merchant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:545,question:"Which of the following is NOT a means of payment through the post office?",option:{a:"Giro system",b:"Money order",c:"Postage stamp",d:"Standing order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:546,question:"Branch managers who virtually have no control on goods they sell is a disadvantage of __  store.",option:{a:"chain",b:"departmental",c:"mail order",d:"super"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:547,question:"Instrument used in place of legal tender but not freely acceptable are called ___ money.",option:{a:"bank",b:"commodity",c:"gold - backed",d:"representative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:548,question:"The assurance policy in which the assured pays lump sum of money which matures at his retirement is ___assurance.",option:{a:"annuity",b:"endowment",c:"life",d:"term"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:549,question:"By making it possible for wholesalers to keep surplus stock until demand improves, the warehouse performs the function of",option:{a:"employment creation",b:"price stabilization",c:"production planning",d:"storage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:550,question:"Calculate the net profit.",option:{a:"30,000",b:"33,000",c:"38,000",d:"40,000"},section:"The following information was extracted from the books of Rubies Enterprises Limited as at31st December 2010. Sales [115,000], Creditors [15,000], Bank overdraft [5,000], Stock [10,000], Cost of goods sold [75,000], Debenture [35,000]; Prepayments [5,000], Rent [ 2,000 ]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:551,question:"Calculate the total liabilities.",option:{a:"40,000",b:"50,000",c:"55,000",d:"57,000"},section:"The following information was extracted from the books of Rubies Enterprises Limited as at31st December 2010. Sales [115,000], Creditors [15,000], Bank overdraft [5,000], Stock [10,000], Cost of goods sold [75,000], Debenture [35,000]; Prepayments [5,000], Rent [ 2,000 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:552,question:"Calculate the current assets.",option:{a:"15,000",b:"20,000",c:"30,000",d:"45,000"},section:"The following information was extracted from the books of Rubies Enterprises Limited as at31st December 2010. Sales [115,000], Creditors [15,000], Bank overdraft [5,000], Stock [10,000], Cost of goods sold [75,000], Debenture [35,000]; Prepayments [5,000], Rent [ 2,000 ]",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:553,question:"Ensuring free movement of factors of production among member states through the removal of obstacles is one of 		the objectives of",option:{a:"ECOWAS",b:"LCBC",c:"NBC",d:"OAU"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:554,question:"Which of the following documents contains the name of the company, registration number and signature of the registrar?",option:{a:"Articles of association",b:"Certificate of incorporation",c:"Certificate of trading",d:"Memorandum of association"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:555,question:"The method of shopping on the internet by using the computer to browse the website of the manufacturer is known as",option:{a:"e-banking",b:"e-commerce",c:"e-exchange",d:"e-trade"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:556,question:"The development of a container and a graphic design for a product is known as",option:{a:"advertising",b:"branding",c:"packaging",d:"trade mark"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:557,question:"When an agent is appointed verbally or in writing by the principal to act on his behalf, the appointment is said to be by",option:{a:"estoppels",b:"express",c:"implication",d:"ratification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:558,question:"The features of an entrepreneur consist of the following, EXCEPT",option:{a:"coordinating factors of production",b:"earning wages as income",c:"efficiency in management",d:"maintaining good communication"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:559,question:"Another name for trade discount is _________ discount,",option:{a:"cash",b:"functional",c:"quality",d:"quantity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:560,question:"Those engaged in extraction, manufacturing, and construction occupations are called ___ workers.",option:{a:"commercial",b:"direct",c:"indirect",d:"industrial"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:561,question:"Which of these is NOT a source of capital to First Bank of Nigeria Plc?",option:{a:"Equipment leasing",b:"Lean from friends",c:"Profit plough back",d:"Sales of shares"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:562,question:"In trading, profit and loss account, carriage outward is",option:{a:"added to purchases",b:"deducted from purchases",c:"deducted from sales",d:"treated as expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:563,question:"The pricing policy adopted by firms selling to wealthy people is",option:{a:"market penetration",b:"market skimming",c:"pricing above the market",d:"pricing with the market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:564,question:"Which of the following is NOT a function of courier companies?",option:{a:"Ensuring international transmission of message",b:"Providing door to door delivery services",c:"Providing efficient means of mail delivery",d:"Undertaking the shipment of export and import"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:565,question:"“MTN, Your Best Connection” is an example of ___ advertisement.",option:{a:"competitive",b:"direct",c:"informative",d:"mass"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:566,question:"The assertion ‘consumers are always right’ refers to marketing",option:{a:"board.",b:"concept",c:"function",d:"mix"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:567,question:"Which of the following is charged by the NIPOST on postal order?",option:{a:"Dividend",b:"Interest",c:"Poundage",d:"Premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:568,question:"The following are characteristics of debenture holders, EXCEPT",option:{a:"being one of the sources of long term loan to public companies.",b:"being paid interest",c:"they are creditors of the company",d:"they are entitled to profits"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:569,question:"The money paid to savings account holders by banks after a period of transaction is called",option:{a:"dividend",b:"gain",c:"interest",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:570,question:"Double coincidence of wants is a disadvantage of",option:{a:"business",b:"buying and selling",c:"credit sales",d:"trade by barter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:571,question:"Price quotation which excludes all delivery charges is called",option:{a:"cost and freight",b:"ex - ship",c:"ex - warehouse",d:"free - on - board"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:572,question:"Which of the following does NOT appear on a cheque on presentation for payment?",option:{a:"Amount in words and figures",b:"Date of withdrawal",c:"Name of the cashier",d:"Name of the payee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:573,question:"The aspect of production which provides goods and services for immediate consumption is called ___ production.",option:{a:"direct",b:"indirect",c:"primary",d:"secondary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:574,question:"The actual gain made by a business after all expenses has been deducted is called",option:{a:"gross profit",b:"margin",c:"mark-up",d:"net profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:575,question:"The following documents are used between buyers and sellers, EXCEPT",option:{a:"catalogue",b:"dispatch rate",c:"invoice",d:"license"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:576,question:"The total assets of a business less current liabilities refers to _____ capital.",option:{a:"authorized",b:"called up",c:"employed",d:"owned"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:577,question:"The following are merits of industrial integration, EXCEPT",option:{a:"controlling output and price",b:"eliminating waste",c:"leading to monopoly",d:"preventing over production"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:578,question:"The use of middlemen by manufacturers become necessary where the goods",option:{a:"are of low rate of turnover",b:"are susceptible to faking or adulteration",c:"involved are branded",d:"produced are in large quantities"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:579,question:"The oldest form of business enterprise in Nigeria is",option:{a:"partnership",b:"private liability company",c:"public enterprise",d:"sole proprietorship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:580,question:"Social responsibilities of a business to the consumers 	include the following, EXCEPT",option:{a:"educating the customers",b:"ensuring truth in advertisement",c:"granting credit facilities",d:"providing of quality product"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:581,question:"Products that have stayed long on themselves in a shop can be sold easily through",option:{a:"branding",b:"discounting",c:"doorstep selling",d:"franchising"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:582,question:"The durable capital of an enterprise which is used continuously for further production is called ___ capital.",option:{a:"called up",b:"circulating",c:"fixed",d:"liquid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:583,question:"A manufacturer is said to have performed all the necessary marketing functions in the distribution channel when the goods move from",option:{a:"manufacturer ? consumer",b:"manufacturer ? retailer ? consumer",c:"manufacturer ? wholesaler ? retailer ? consumer",d:"manufacturer ? wholesaler ?jobber ? retailer ?consumer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:584,question:"Which of the following is NOT a reason for government’s ownership of Nigerian Ports Authority (NPA)?",option:{a:"Avoiding wasteful competition and duplication",b:"Generating revenue",c:"High capital requirement",d:"Making profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:585,question:"The first step for a businessman who wishes to engage in international trade is to",option:{a:"ask the exporter to move the goods to the shipping company for delivery",b:"engage the services of clearing agent to clear the goods on his behalf",c:"establish contact with the foreign trading partner",d:"fill an application for import form with a bank"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:586,question:"A law made by a country to prohibit importation of certain goods into the country is called _____ laws.",option:{a:"export",b:"import",c:"protectionist",d:"tariff"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:587,question:"Which of the following towns was NOT an initial commercial centre in Nigeria?",option:{a:"Kano",b:"Lagos",c:"Maiduguri",d:"Yola"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:588,question:"Management function which arranges people, time, money and equipment, to achieve the objectives of an organization is referred to as",option:{a:"directing",b:"motivating",c:"organizing",d:"planning"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:589,question:"Bridging the gap between producers and consumers is the sole purpose of",option:{a:"distribution",b:"hawking",c:"retailing",d:"warehousing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:590,question:"Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of labour? It is",option:{a:"fixed in supply",b:"geographically mobile",c:"man made",d:"perishable in nature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:591,question:"One of the problems associated with home trade is the",option:{a:"absence of currency exchange",b:"better knowledge of the markets",c:"inadequacy of storage facilities",d:"proximity of buyers and sellers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:592,question:"An instruction from a current account holder requesting to pay a named person or organization a. specified amount is 		called",option:{a:"bankers order",b:"certified cheque",c:"internal transfer",d:"money order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:593,question:"Which of the following is NOT a commercial occupation?",option:{a:"Advertising",b:"Agriculture",c:"Communication",d:"Insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:594,question:"In the marketing mix, place refers to",option:{a:"channel of distribution",b:"location of the factory",c:"the market place",d:"where the product is located"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:595,question:"Which of the following is NOT an attribute of an effective business manager?",option:{a:"Altruism",b:"Empathy",c:"Objectivity",d:"Subjectivity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:596,question:"The ability of money to be divided into smaller units for easy exchange of goods and services explains",option:{a:"divisibility",b:"durability",c:"recognisability",d:"stability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:597,question:"Which of the following is NOT a role of trade association?",option:{a:"Eliminating competition among members",b:"Ensuring uniformity in mode of operation",c:"Establishing link between government and associations",d:"Promoting members interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:598,question:"The transfer of enterprises from private to state ownership for economic or social reasons is referred to as",option:{a:"commercialization",b:"indigenization",c:"industrialization",d:"naturalization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"}],a={subject:e,status:200,total:108,data:o};export{o as data,a as default,i as status,e as subject,t as total};
